♪
♪ see the curtains hanging in the window ♪
♪ people trying not alive ♪
♪ a little light a-shining in the window ♪
♪ lets me know everything 's all right ♪
♪ summer breeze .
♪ Makes me feel fine .
♪ Blowing through the Jasmine
♪ in my mind
♪ summer breeze
♪ makes me feel fine
♪ blowing through the Jasmine
♪ in my mind
[ chimes ]
- [ Wind whistling ] - [ Crunching ]
[ Rocks tumbling ] [ Birds squawking ]
[ Piercing whistle ]
♪ [ " Stars and stripes forever " ]
[ Noisemakers blaring ] [ Crowd cheering , chattering ]
[ Man on microphone ] I tell you what .
That 's got to be the prettiest girl we 've ever had in competition .
I tell ya .
Now let 's welcome back our six finalists onstage .
Come on back out , girls . [ Crowd clapping , cheering ]
There they are . They 're as pretty as they can be , aren 't they ? I 'll tell you .
We 're proud of you , girls . You worked hard . Your mamas and daddies have worked hard .
We 're mighty proud of you .
[ Cheering , whistling continue ] All right !
Whoo-hoo !
God , look at her . I mean , she was born for this .
I had no idea her breasts were so ample .
[ Laughs ] Dude , she does these exercises that pump ' em up .
Guys , hi . I 'm on sexist overload as it is .
Kill the commentary .
Now , in the spirit of mother Teresa ,
what will be your contribution to your community and the world at large ?
Well , Bob , at summer 's end I plan to move to New York City ,
where I 'll pursue a career as a serious actress .
It 's my goal to entertain the world through artistic expression .
Through art , I shall serve my country .
[ Crowd cheering ]
Do you feed her this shit ?
Work it , babe .
Man , they 're eatin ' it up . Look , she 's incredible .
And now , this year 's Croaker Queen is ...
Miss Helen Shivers !
[ Crowd applauds , screams ] ♪ [ " Anchors aweigh " ]
Yeah ! Yeah , that 's my girl ! That 's my girl !
[ Inaudible chattering ]
That 's my girlfriend ! Helen !
[ Laughing ] [ Squealing ]
Yeah , baby , yeah !
♪ My baby 's got the strangest ways of saying ♪
♪ whoo , whoo , whoo , whoo
♪ my baby 's got the strangest ways of saying ♪
♪ a strip of jerky long and lean ♪
♪ serve it up with a side of mean ♪
♪ my baby 's got the strangest ways of saying ♪
♪ whoo , whoo , whoo , whoo
how 's my hair ? Hurricane-proof .
Hey , it 's all about the hair . Don 't you forget that .
Especially when you become some big hotshot lawyer .
Those professional women types think it 's all about brains and ability ...
And completely ignore the " do " .
So , the " do 's " vital . Got it .
[ Both laugh ]
Hey , you ridin ' with me ? Uh , no , tell mom I 'll be late .
Uh , is little Miss Croaker getting sauteed tonight ?
Ho , a twit with a wit . Eat me .
Hey , Julie . Brought you a shooter on the house .
Oh , thanks , Max , but you know what , I have this mental block .
I can 't get past the slime . How ' bout I take you out before you leave town ?
You know , kind of a bon voyage thing .
Oh , uh- -
you know what- - I-I don 't , I don 't think so , Max .
We 've been friends since forever .
Now , you can 't just leave without a farewell , right ? Right .
A toast to us .
To our last summer of ...
Immature , adolescent decadence .
[ Laughter ] [ Helen ] Somebody 's buzzed .
[ Laughs ]
Yo , chum bait , take a hike . Hey ! Hey !
[ Grunts ] Hey , easy ! Easy !
Hey ! Come on , man . Barry , they 're just friends .
Man , this is tired .
Hey , Ray , just taking care of your girl like I promised .
Thanks , buddy . Let 's blow .
Yeah , hey , let 's beam down to Dawson 's beach . Little joyride .
Good-bye .
♪ [ The offspring : " D.U.I. " ] [ Tires screeching ]
[ Ray ] So the boy and girl are making out , right ,
when they hear over the radio that this lunatic killer 's escaped from an insane asylum .
He 's got this long , sharp hook for a hand , right ?
[ Barry ] Dude , your tellin ' it wrong .
[ Ray ] Shut up . So the girl , she gets all scared , right ?
She wants to go home . And the boy , all hot and bothered ,
he gets pissed and peels out . [ Barry ] Wait . No , no , no .
That 's not the way it goes . Okay , the boy goes for help ,
and the girl stays in the car , and she hears this , like , scratching sound- -
it 's not a scratching sound . It 's a drip . Drip , drip .
No , it 's scratching because the guy 's been hung ...
From a tree and his feet are scratching on the car . No .
He 's been decapitated , and it 's the blood from his severed neck ...
That 's dripping on the car , and it 's going , drip , drip , drip .
No , he wasn 't decapitated . He was gutted with a hook .
That 's the way I heard it .
Look , you 're all wrong .
They get back to the girl 's house , and they find ...
The lunatic 's bloody hook in the car door .
Now , that 's the original story . That 's the way it really happened .
Hey , hey . None of it really happened .
- It 's a bullshit ghost story to begin with . - No , it 's not .
It 's true . [ Helen ] Yeah , I don 't think so , Ray .
I swear it . Please .
It 's a fictional story created to warn young girls ...
Of the dangers of having premarital sex .
[ Ray ] Well , actually , honey- -
and you know how terrified I am of your I.Q. , but- -
it 's an urban legend , American folklore .
And they all usually originate from some sort of real-life incident .
[ Wave breaks loudly ]
[ Yelling , laughing ]
So , by that time ,
i will just be finishing my two-year contract on guiding light ,
coinciding with your first year as starting quarterback for the steelers .
Cowboys . Whoever .
Then , we can elope to Europe , or the Caymans ,
wherever , where I 'll let you impregnate me ...
With the first of three children ... [ Laughs ] [ Grunts ]
Before you head off to rehab .
And then we can live happily ,
blah , blah , blah .
[ Julie ] Ray ? Ray ?
Where 'd you go ? [ Footsteps approaching quickly ]
[ Ray ] I 'm gonna hook you ! [ Screams , laughs ]
Hey , Ray , you don 't really believe all that crap , do you ? That 's true .
Please , the hook is really a phallic symbol .
Oh , really ? Yeah , ultimately castrated .
[ Giggles ] God , I 'm gonna miss you .
You don 't have to . You can always ditch this Boston thing ,
and , uh , come to New York with me .
Yeah , well , we can 't all sit in a village coffee house and ramble esoterically on our laptops .
There just isn 't enough room .
See , nobody gets me the way you do . I understand your pain .
Precisely . I hate this . I really hate this .
You 're gonna go off , and you 're gonna fall for some head-shaven ,
black-wearing , tattoo-covered , body-piercing philosophy student .
That sounds attractive .
And I 'll never see you again . Hey !
Did you know the success rate of high school sweetheart relationships ...
Is higher than any other type of relationship ?
Yeah ? Cite your source .
Are you sure ?
♪ Kings and queens
♪ from a fortress of sheets ♪
♪ watch tv
♪ they may hear us in magazines ♪
Okay , man , but give me the keys . You 're-you 're toast .
Whose car is this ? N-nobody drives my car but me .
I-I-I know , baby . Um , but the Croaker Queen has to get home now .
Thank you . Hey , you two .
Give me my fuckin ' keys . You 're trashed , pal .
All right . Come on . Come ride in the back with me . I 'll let you do things to me .
Mm-hmm , mm-hmm . Nobody drives my car but me .
You got that , shit smear ? Loud and clear .
Get in the car .
♪ [ Car radio , indistinct ]
[ Laughter ]
[ Helen ] Here . Jesus !
You can 't drive for shit , you know that ?
- God . - Can you say " alcoholic " ?
♪ How are the reasons
♪ pushed through the sound track ♪
All right , what the hell is this crap ? [ Presses button ]
♪ [ Raucous drumbeat , loud rock ] [ Yells ]
[ Screams ] Yeah !
- Barry . - [ Continues screaming ]
- Hey ! - You asshole !
What 's wrong with you ?
Watch out !
[ Tires screeching ]
[ Helen ] What was that ? [ Ray ] I don 't know .
[ Julie ] Is everybody okay ? [ Moans ]
[ Ray ] I think it was an animal .
[ Helen ] God , you 're bleeding !
It 's not mine . It must 've been a dog or something .
Jesus Christ , my fuckin ' car !
You fuck ! Can 't you see where you 're goin ' ?
Look , it-it came out of nowhere . I didn 't see it !
A dog couldn 't have done that . Yeah , well , a fuckin ' deer could .
Look , you dropped your bottle . I was just trying to- - my dad is going to freak .
Barry , it was an accident . Leave him alone .
Where is it ? If it was a deer , then where is it ?
[ Ray ] Look , m-maybe it ran off .
[ Helen ] I hope so . I hope we didn 't kill it . Fuck that . Let 's go .
Oh , my God !
- [ Breathing heavily ] - No way .
Oh , my God . But I thought-
[ Ray ] I didn 't see it . - No , there 's no way !
Oh , my God , this isn 't happening !
You check that side . Yeah .
Come on . Helen .
[ Screams ] No !
I couldn 't see it ! Look , I swear !
Is he dead ? I don 't know .
Check his pulse . No way !
You 're the one who rammed him ! Just do it !
I think he 's dead .
Shit ! Fuck !
Who is he ?
I can 't tell . His face is all messed up .
What the hell was he doing out here ?
[ Julie ] We 've gotta call the police and get an ambulance out here .
Hey , hey , what 's your hurry ?
The guy 's dead .
You 're not a doctor . You don 't make that decision .
Use your brain , Julie . We call the police , and we 're fucked .
- It was an accident . - Look , let 's think about this a minute .
Think about what ? Think about what ?
He was crossing the road in the middle of the night , okay ?
It was an accident . You weren 't drinking or speeding .
There 's liquor all over the car . But you 're sober .
- They 'll never believe I was driving . - It 's my car .
They 'll nail my ass . That 's not true .
Are you kidding ? Look at me .
I 'm drunk as shit . I 'm fucked .
No , we 'll call the police . We 'll tell them the truth !
- They 'll believe us . - It 's manslaughter .
- We 're gonna fry no matter who takes the fall . - Then we leave right now .
No way . Are you crazy ?
- The grill 's busted . There 's blood everywhere . - We can clean it up . Come on .
Listen to yourselves . No , we are going to the police !
We don 't have time for your shit ! We gotta move fast !
Hey ! Now , let 's try to stay calm .
Focus . Don 't you get it ?
If there 's some of him on the car , there 's some of the car on him .
They 're gonna trace it back to you . You 're looking at a hit-and-run .
Then we dump the body .
You 've lost it . Look , just pretend we were never here .
We could drag him to the water and dump him in .
They wouldn 't find the fucker for weeks .
By that time all the evidence would be washed away .
If they found him at all .
The currents are strong . The undertow- - it could carry him out to sea .
[ Sighs disgustedly ] I won 't be any part of it .
Look , I 'm scared , Julie . I 'm not like the rest of you .
I don 't have your family or the money to get me out of this .
- Please . - This is your future , Julie .
Think about it .
College . There 's your scholarship .
The guy 's already dead . If we go to the police , we 're dead too .
[ Tires squealing ] Fuck .
What do we do ? Help me .
[ Gasping ]
Shit , they 're slowing down !
- [ Helen ] Who is it ? - It 's Max .
Get rid of him !
Julie , what you got , car trouble ?
- Actually , um- - - [ Retching noises , coughing ]
It 's Barry . He 's had way too much to drink .
And we 're trying to keep the upchuck out of the new car .
- [ Max ] Well , it doesn 't look so new anymore . - Yeah , don 't drink and drive .
Daddy 's gonna be mad . [ Laughs ]
- What can I do for you , Max ? - You can wipe that " my shit don 't stink " grin off .
Okay , Max . Will do . Have a good night .
Y-you almost got that rich boy act down , Ray .
We 'll be seeing you , Max .
Yep . Take care , Julie .
[ Barry ] Even if his body washes ashore in the next couple of weeks ,
it 'll be eaten by crabs and small fish .
Maybe we 'll get lucky with a shark .
Take him to the side .
Put him down . [ Ray ] Easy .
That 's it .
- Let 's do it . - Wait .
What ?
Should we check his wallet and see who he is ?
- Why ? - I don 't know , okay ?
- Just to know . - I don 't wanna know .
Let 's just pretend he 's some escaped lunatic ...
With a hook for a hand , and we 're doing everybody a favor .
Ray , help me .
- I don 't think I can , Barry . - Shit ! We agreed .
- Come on , Barry . It 's not too late . - You ! Shut up !
- Just shut up ! - Christ already , I 'll do it !
[ Julie screams ] Help ! Get him off of me !
- Get him ! - [ Screams ]
[ Helen ] My crown ! He 's got my crown ! [ Barry yells ]
No !
Barry ! Barry !
[ Muffled scream ]
[ Ray ] Over here !
[ Grunting ]
Ooh !
Let 's get out of here . We 're going home now ,
and never ever , under any circumstances ...
Known to God , speak about this again .
Is that clear ?
It is now merely a future therapy bill , agreed ?
Helen !
I 'll never mention it again .
We make a pact , right here and now . We take this to our grave .
Agreed .
Julie ?
Don 't you nod your head . You fuckin ' say it !
Yeah , okay .
We take this to our grave ! Let me hear it ! Let her go , Barry !
You fuckin ' say it . [ Panting ]
Okay , Barry , we take this to the grave .
It 'll be okay .
[ Exhales ] [ Door opens ]
[ Door shuts ]
[ Engine starts ]
[ Tires squealing ]
♪ She 'd talk
♪ of standing in the rain ♪
♪ no fault and doing it again ♪
♪ some kind of happiness is measured out in Miles ♪
♪ what makes you think you 're something special when you smile ♪
Yo , it 's time to go .
Come on .
Move your tired , ugly ass , girl . We 're late .
I changed my mind . I 'm not going .
Julie , get your white-as-death ,
chalky corpse in the car now .
I said , " come on . "
Julie , you 're going home for the summer ,
and you 're gonna get a tan on that pasty-pale tail of yours .
[ Laughs ] Let 's go .
Remember . Sun and fun .
Yeah . Yeah .
[ Woman ] Julie ?
Welcome home , dear .
I missed you .
[ Mother ] How 's the snapper ?
I-I really wanted monkfish , but , uh , it 's been a bad season and- -
are you on drugs ?
What ?
I just wanted to surprise you . I want an honest reaction .
No .
No , mom . No drugs .
Well , then , what is wrong ? I mean , you look like death .
Yeah , well , I 've had a rough year .
You got some mail . A letter came today .
It 's not your report card , though . That came last week .
Mom , I know it looks bad , but the summer session went really well .
Well , it would have to , because according to the Dean , you only have one more chance .
It 's not that serious . Really .
What happened to my daughter ?
I mean , you went away , and you don 't call and you don 't visit .
Your father must be turning over in his grave .
[ Gasping ]
Who sent this ?
Uh , there 's no postmark or return address .
Your guess is as good as mine . Why , what does it say ?
Nothing .
[ Dog barking , rattling ]
[ Barking continues ]
[ Wind whistling ] [ Leaves rustling ]
[ Metal chimes ]
♪ You start having a great life ♪
♪ it 's about living with inspiration ♪
♪ start having a great life ♪
Guys , easy . It 's called glass . It breaks .
Good morning . Hi .
[ Bell ringing ]
Well , well . Look what the cat dragged in .
Elsa , hi .
You know what ? I need to talk to Helen , and I was wondering ...
If you could give me her New York number ? Her New York number .
Yeah , I need to talk to her .
Fact check , Julie . Helen doesn 't have a New York number .
If you need to speak with her , I suggest you go to women 's fragrances ,
ten feet to your left .
[ Crashing ]
Frightening , isn 't it ?
Julie ?
Wh-when did you get home ?
Yesterday .
It 's good to see you . What happened to New York ?
I went for a while . It , um- - it didn 't really work out .
Somebody sent this to me .
- Oh , my God . - Somebody knows , Helen .
How ?
- I don 't know . - Julie , we were so careful .
Were we ? Were we ?
What if somebody saw us ? What if somebody else was there that night ?
- Who ? It 's been a year . - I don 't know .
H-has Barry seen this ?
[ Helen ] Do you ever see Barry at school ?
[ Julie ] It 's a big campus . Are you sure he came back ?
I saw his car the other day at the gym .
Did you guys break up ?
Hey !
What are you two doin ' here ?
Hi , Bar .
This is nothing . " I know what you did last summer " ?
- Ooh . What a crock of shit . - We need help .
Yeah , I 'll say . You know , you guys should check out a mirror once in a while .
- You two look like shit run over twice . - You 're a prick .
We can 't just ignore it .
Come on , Julie . How do you know this is even related ?
You did a lot of things last summer .
- Yeah , well , only one murder comes to mind . - You shut the hell up !
- [ Chattering ] - We didn 't murder anyone .
He was still alive when we dumped him in the water . Do we have to rehash this ?
It was an accident . The guy was in the middle of the road .
- His name was David Egan . - Who ?
David Egan .
He was found three weeks after we- -
his body was caught in a shrimp net not far from Miller 's dock .
It was in the paper .
I think the police called it an accidental drowning .
You can call it an accident all you want , but he died because of us . That 's certain .
What about Ray ?
Have you shown this letter to him ? What does he think ?
I haven 't seen Ray since last summer .
We broke up , and last I heard he was working up north .
Okay , let 's suppose somebody was there that night .
Why send a letter one year later ?
Probably some crack fuckin ' around .
Max .
Max , what- - you think ?
Who else ? He was there .
[ Man ] Bring that other pallet .
You two wait here . What are you gonna do ?
I know what I 'm doin ' .
[ Man shouting , indistinct , distant ]
Well , go figure .
You know , I was just thinking to myself , " whatever happened to that Barry Cox ? "
Hey , Max .
Listen , can we talk a sec , in private ?
Oh , what , this isn 't private enough for you ?
[ Laughs ]
Yeah , what ?
Ow ! Look , you shit , we got your little letter .
What the hell are you talking about ? Don 't fuck with me , Max .
You saw us that night . What the fuck are you on , huh ?
Jesus ! Listen , I 'm gonna say this once .
I 'll fuckin ' kill your ass . I got no problem with that . Oh , get the fuck off me .
Get off of me . Understand ?
Ah ! Shit .
Motherfucker !
Don 't you test me , motherfucker !
I 'll call the cops on your college quarterback ass !
[ Helen ] So , did he admit to the letter ? He won 't bother you anymore .
What did you do ? I took care of it , okay ?
How ? I scared the shit out of him , all right ?
[ Barry ] Well , I 'll be damned .
[ Horn blowing ]
[ Man ] Put another container on it ! Hi .
So , Ray grew up to be a fisherman , huh ?
Yeah , almost a year now . I work on that one over there , on the end .
That 's nice . Have a nice life , guys . I 'm outta here .
You got a minute ?
I gotta get back to work .
Call me . We can get together .
Yeah , okay .
W-we need to talk .
Do you think Max sent it ? Barry does . I don 't know .
Well , you know how Max feels about you guys .
Look , he 's probably just screwing around . He doesn 't have much else to do .
Yeah , maybe .
So , how 's school ?
So , you 're a fisherman .
Yeah , prophecy fulfilled , right ?
I 've become my father . I thought you didn 't know your dad .
Ah , he worked the boats . That 's all I do know about him .
[ Horn blowing ] Look , I thought a lot about last summer .
I know you hold me responsible for what happened . I don 't hold you responsible .
No , I 'm responsible for my own actions , and I don 't blame you .
But I don 't want to know you , either .
Ah ! Fuck !
[ Gasps ]
[ Gurgling ]
♪ [ Rock , indistinct ]
♪ Hush , hush she broke my heart but I love her just the same now ♪
♪ early in the morning or late in the evening ♪
♪ oh , I got to believe you honey ♪
[ Grunts ]
[ Continues grunting ]
♪ Hush , hush I thought I heard you calling my name now ♪
♪ now hush , hush
[ locker clanking ]
Hello ?
[ Metal chimes ]
Hey !
[ Locker door rattles ]
Fuck .
My fuckin ' jacket .
Hey , Hank , who else is here ? Anybody else working out ?
Just you and me , pal .
[ Engine revving ]
Hey , hey !
Fucker !
[ Tires squealing ]
Max , you 're fuckin ' dead .
[ Panting ]
[ Engine revving ]
[ Grunts ]
[ Screams ]
[ Groans ]
[ Car door closes ]
Help me !
Help me ! Somebody !
What do you want ?
[ Gasping , crying ]
I 'm sorry , I 'm sorry . I swear , we didn 't mean it . Please .
Please don 't .
One moment , please , officer .
Mm-hmm . [ Elevator bell ringing ]
Julie . [ Gasps ]
What happened ?
No , for the 40th fucking time , I couldn 't see his face .
We have no choice here , okay ? Somebody tried to kill you last night .
- We have to go to the police . - No , he wasn 't trying to kill me last night .
If he wanted me dead , he could 've done it . He 's just fuckin ' with us .
- Who is ? - I don 't know . Some guy in a slicker .
Well , that narrows it down , this being a quaint little fishing village and all .
And since you bring it up ,
we all know you have a slicker .
You are not gonna throw this on me .
No , guys , please don 't do this . This isn 't getting us anywhere !
[ Sighs ]
Look , maybe we should just come clean .
No . No , we made a pact , and we 're gonna keep it .
Yeah , but that 's insane now , Barry . Look at us . This secret 's killing us .
I 'm not going to the police , and you 're not either .
Barry , please . We could put an end to it ...
And maybe salvage some small fraction of a life .
And how do we do that , huh ? There was no accident , Julie .
It was murder . Your words , remember ? Murder .
I say we find the fuck who 's doing this and have a little one-on-one .
- What , like last night , Bar ? - Fuck you !
No , Barry 's right . Whoever 's doing this isn 't going to the police .
We could find this guy , talk to him .
How do we find him ?
Well , it 's gotta be a friend or a family member of the guy we hit .
What was his name ?
David Egan . Right .
David Egan .
Look , I don 't think we should give up on Max .
I mean , it could still be him . Then find him , Ray .
Prove Barry wrong . That 's what you want , isn 't it ?
No . Now , what I want is for you and me to just- - listen to me , Ray , okay ?
I want you to get something . There is no " you and me " .
[ Woman on intercom ] Dr. Brown . Dr. Brown .
[ Julie ] Okay , I can access the local library on-line .
I think we can cross-reference and pull up all we need to know .
Egan , David .
- [ Helen ] All these articles are about David Egan ? - Yeah , or at least mention him .
It should pull up anything with his name . [ Computer beeps ]
Wait , July 5 . Two years ago . What 's this ?
[ Julie ] " Susie Willis died of drowning .
" She was trapped in a car after it skidded out of control ...
" In the reefs near Dawson 's beach .
The driver , David Egan , was unharmed . " I remember that wreck .
[ Julie ] " Susie was engaged to David . They were going to be married . "
Wait a second . I remember he had her name tattooed on his arm . I saw it .
" Survived by his mother Claire and sister Melissa Egan of Maribel county . "
They live in the sticks . What do you think ?
What have we got to lose ?
[ Helen ] Turn right . Where ?
Back there .
♪ A melancholy
♪ butterfly just cries
♪ tears that sting
what exactly is the plan ?
Are we gonna ring the doorbell and say , " we killed your son , we 're in the neighborhood , so- - "
look , I thought we 'd scope it out , then play it by ear .
Don 't you think we should have some sort of a plan ?
Angela Lansbury always had a plan .
What if they 're waiting for us ?
What if they recognize us ? They could have a gun , shoot us dead .
It 's been a year , Helen . They could 've done that already .
Jodie Foster tried this , and a serial killer answered the door .
Well , it was a good try .
[ Birds chirping ]
Adding breaking and entering to our crime spree ?
Can I help you ?
Oh , um , hi . Our car stalled down the road ,
and we were just wondering if maybe we could use your phone ?
Phone 's over there . Oh , thanks .
Um , Jody ,
will you call Triple A ?
You got it , Angela .
[ Gasps ]
[ Laughs ]
My name is Missy Egan . Are you girls from Maribel ?
Oh , Southport . Uh , I went to Southport High .
Yeah , I-I knew you looked familiar . Wh-what year ?
- Uh , class of ' 88 . - Your name , Egan , sounds very familiar .
Did you have a brother or something ? I did , but he was younger .
David . Younger .
- What class was he ? - Uh , ' 92 , but he 's dead . He died last July .
I 'm-I 'm so sorry .
- Thanks . - D-do you , uh , do you live alone ?
Yeah , I do .
Uh , well , my daddy died a long time ago , and my mama , she 's ...
In a home in Aurora , because she didn 't take too well to what happened to David .
Things just haven 't been the same since he died .
They 're on their way .
I could , uh- - I could make you guys a cup of tea while you 're waitin ' .
- Thanks . - Yeah , thanks . That-that 's nice of you .
[ Helen ] You know , I think I remember David .
He had a friend , right ? What was his name ?
Who ?
Didn 't he hang out with this guy ? And they were really close .
- God , what was his name ? Um . - Oh , I-I-I don 't know .
I didn 't- - I didn 't know too many of David 's friends .
Oh .
But there was one guy , one guy .
He-he stopped by not too long after David 's death ,
and-and he came to pay his respects .
- Really ? - Oh , yeah . He was a really nice guy .
He was cute and smart and- -
well , we were- - we were sweet on each other ...
For about two minutes , but it didn 't work out .
You know , he did- - he never really said it , but I think it hurt him to be around me .
Where is this old friend now ?
Oh , I- - I don 't know .
Do you remember his name ? Billy .
Did he have a last name ? Blue . Billy Blue .
Well , you know what ? We should probably wait back at the car .
No , don 't be ridiculous . Why don 't- - uh , stay .
No , I-I don 't , I don 't want to miss Triple A.
We appreciate the phone . Anytime , you know .
I-I don 't get too many knocks on my door nowadays .
You okay ?
I wigged out . I 'm sorry .
But being in his house and seeing his sister- -
God . Do you see what we 've done ?
It was an accident .
Helen , we killed a man , and then ruined the lives of everyone he knew .
I don 't think we 're that powerful , Julie . You 're giving us too much credit .
Hey !
You forgot your cigarettes . Thank you .
Well , I see you 've got this car started , didn 't you ?
Yeah , damnedest thing . It started right up . Funny how that happens .
So , what now ?
Now we try and locate this Billy Blue .
Maybe he wanted to die .
What ? David Egan .
His girlfriend was killed on that same road July 4 , one year earlier .
Maybe he blamed himself . Maybe he was sitting in the road waiting for us to hit him .
Yeah , if that will help you sleep at night .
What happened between us ?
We used to be best friends .
We used to be a lot of things .
I miss you .
Yeah , well .
[ Tv commentator # 1 ] Low in the dirt , ball two .
[ Commentator # 2 ] Garrett doesn 't seem to have his typical control today , Greg .
In fact , this is as wild as we 've ever seen him in the season .
[ Greg ] That 's right , Dave . In fact , over the last three games ,
he 's only allowed three bases on balls , not one of those runners ever scoring .
Pretty remarkable indeed as neale steps back into the box- -
hey , dad . One to nothing here in the third .
Garrett taking his time . Here 's the pitch .
Strike one . [ Dave ] Wicked cut . Neale seemed fooled by that pitch .
In fact , in addition to the split-fingered fastball- -
[ continues , indistinct ]
[ Greg ] Ready now with the sign and the pitch . Fouled off .
Strike two . Last year , neale would 've been sending that pitch ...
Over to the next county . [ Dave ] It 's true .
[ Commentary continues , indistinct ]
[ Greg ] And the pitch . Very high and very inside .
[ Dave ] I don 't know what it is .
[ Greg ] I couldn 't agree more , as the count is full now at three and two .
Garrett settling himself , looking at the sign .
Here 's the windup .
There 's a smash up the middle ! [ Continues , indistinct ]
They got him ! [ Dave ] Nice play at second . Wow , what a play .
[ Commentary continues , indistinct ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Faint breathing ]
[ Gasps ] Hey , is the washed-up , dried-out has-been having a moment ?
What do you want ?
We 're doing inventory at the store tomorrow . I need you there by 10 : 00 .
I can 't . I 'm in the parade tomorrow .
Well , dad put me in charge of the store , and I want you there by 10 : 00 .
The outgoing queen has to ride in the parade prior to the pageant .
It 's tradition . There 's nothing I can do about it .
You and your hair . It is so pathetic .
You can leave now .
So very pathetic .
[ Sighs ]
[ Whimpering ]
[ Gasping ]
[ Breathing heavily , whimpering ]
[ Crying ]
[ Screams ] No !
No ! No ! No !
[ Telephone rings ]
Hello ?
What ? Oh , my God .
[ Scratching , shuffling ]
[ Shuffling , scratching resume ]
[ Screaming ]
Max !
[ Crying , hyperventilating ]
[ Horn honking ]
[ Breathing heavily ]
You sure he was dead ? Don 't ask me that again !
He was dead , okay ? I saw him with- - with these crabs .
You do it .
No , don 't even- - he was there , goddamn it ! And he was wearing your jacket , Barry .
Well , where 'd he go ? Did the crabs carry him away ?
I swear to God . I believe you , Julie .
He took the body . He came and he took the body .
- Why would he do that ? - I don 't know , Barry . Okay ?
Why would he try to run you over ? Why did he make coleslaw on Helen 's head ?
- He 's fucking with us ! - Come on , Julie . Let 's go back to the house .
Where 's your jacket , Barry ?
Don 't you see ? He 's got us now .
This is exactly what he wants . We can 't go to the police . Not now . He 's made sure of that .
He 's just out there and he 's watching us and waiting . What are you waiting for , huh ?
[ Screaming ] What are you waiting for ?
What are you doin ' here ?
Hey , I 've been lookin ' everywhere for you guys . You 're gonna die .
Hey , stop it ! What are you doin ' ?
Stop it ! Stop ! I didn 't do anything !
You 're fuckin ' lyin ' . He 's lying !
Leave him alone . Get a grip . No , wake up , Julie ! He 's behind this .
How many fucked-up fishermen are out there ? Look , he 's after me too .
I got a letter .
Oh , you got a letter . I got run over , Helen gets her hair chopped off ,
Julie gets a body in a trunk and you get a letter ?
That 's balanced . What body ? What are you talking- -
drop the act . You killed Max . You took my jacket .
Max is dead ? What is it with you , Ray ?
You were dogging ' us from the start , weren 't you ? Always wanting ' to be our friend ,
but you were too fuckin jealous to handle it .
Look , fuck you ! [ Julie ] Stop it !
Look , we have to stick together , all right ?
We have to help each other .
Okay , so if it 's not fisher boy here , who is it and how do we find him ?
We think his name is Billy Blue .
How do you know that ?
Missy said there was a friend named Billy Blue .
Who probably went to school with David Egan . So , according to sis ,
that would make him class of ' 92 .
Elsa was class of ' 92 .
Maybe there 's something in her yearbook .
That 's him , huh ? It 's hard to believe that 's the guy .
Yeah , his face isn 't splattered all over the road , dumb ass .
Maybe Blue 's not his real name .
That 's right . I mean , he could 've easily lied to Missy . We did .
We should bring the yearbook to Missy . If she had it- - she could point him out .
I 'm not goin ' anywhere .
Wh- - high school mug shots ? Wh- -
I 'll go . You 've got that parade today .
Forget it . No ! No , you need to be there in case he shows up .
I don 't want him to show up ! Look , Helen , this could be our chance .
Okay , we could catch him .
I 'll go to Missy 's . Barry , go to the parade with Helen and don 't let her out of your sight .
If he shows up- - I 'll pound his ass .
Listen to yourselves . You sound like a bunch of vigilantes .
It 's July 4 , Ray . Okay ? This is his day .
Whatever he has planned is gonna happen today unless we stop him .
Look , come on , Julie . Don 't you see ?
It 's that moment where we have to make a decision .
Let 's make the right one this time .
I 'm not interested in what 's right anymore , Ray . I wanna do what 's smart .
Then let 's get the hell out of here . We can leave town , disappear .
I 've already disappeared . Okay , now I want my life back .
Look , we have to face this .
What 's it gonna be , Ray ?
♪ [ " You 're a grand old flag " ]
[ Crowd cheering ]
♪ [ Stops ] [ Whistle blowing ]
♪ [ Marching band resumes ]
[ Cheering continues ]
Barry ? Barry !
Over there !
Move !
Move it !
[ Grunts ]
[ Shuddering ]
Oh , shit !
Where the hell is he ?
♪ [ " Where did you sleep last night " ]
♪ I 'm goin ' where the cold wind blows ♪
[ Knocking ]
Missy ?
♪ Where the sun don 't ever shine ♪
Hello ?
♪ My girl , my girl
♪ don 't you lie to me
♪ tell me where did you sleep last night ♪
♪ [ continues , faintly ]
Hello ?
[ Rooster crows ]
Please . Please .
Missy ?
Missy , do you remember me from the other day ?
You know , the car trouble ? What are you doin ' here ?
[ Chattering ]
Please , we need to talk .
Hmm . I need to find your brother 's friend Billy Blue .
I need to talk to him . I was thinking maybe you could look through this yearbook .
What- - what 's this all about ?
Well , it 's too crazy to explain , but it has to do with your brother and last July 4 .
What about it ?
What happened to your brother wasn 't an accident . There 's more to it than that .
I know . You know what ?
Well , he killed himself .
He what ?
He , uh- - he went up there to die that night . That 's where Susie died .
See , the whole town blamed him for her death .
So , he blamed himself .
But how do you know it was a suicide ?
He left a note .
I had to keep this hidden from the insurance company ' cause they wouldn 't- -
they wouldn 't pay me the money , you know , if it was suicide .
Uh ,
yeah , that don 't much matter anymore because , uh ,
money 's been spent .
That 's it .
This isn 't a suicide note . This is a death threat .
What are you ta- - what are you- - what are you talking about ?
Your brother didn 't kill himself , Missy .
I saw him . I was there . And whoever sent this was there too .
What do you mean ? Where did you see him ? He was crossing the road .
We hit him . It was an accident . No !
- My brother drowned . - I saw him . He had " Susie " tattooed on his arm .
He doesn 't have a tattoo . I saw it on his right forearm .
You didn 't see anything ! Get outta here .
Get out of my house .
Oh , my God .
It wasn 't your brother .
[ Man over microphone ] Testing . One , two , three , four .
Leon , pull it up a little bit . There 's gonna be a lot of people in here who can 't hear it .
Pull it up just- - one , two , three- -
now that 's got it . Don 't nobody mess with it . Leave it right there .
♪ [ Dance rock ]
Cut ' em .
Stay calm . I 'll be up in the balcony .
He had a hook , Barry . I saw it . It was a big , huge hook .
Everything 's gonna be all right .
I 'm not gonna let anything happen to you .
[ Polite applause ] Very nicely done , ladies .
Now , let 's meet last year 's winner , miss Helen Shivers .
[ Man ] Way to go , Helen ! ♪ [ " Beautiful girl " ]
♪ You 'rful girl
♪ you 're a gorgeous mixture of all that lies ♪
♪ under those baby blue eyes
[ emcee ] Now as we continue with our pageant , we move into the talent competition .
All right , ladies .
♪ [ Dance rock ]
[ Baby look at me ♪
♪ and tell me what you see ♪
♪ you ain 't seen the best of me yet ♪
♪ give me time and I 'll make you forget the rest ♪
- ♪ I 've got more to give . - Jesus .
♪ And you can set it free .
♪ I can touch the moon with my hand ♪
♪ don 't you know who I am
♪ remember my name fame ♪
Barry !
- No-o-o-o ! - [ Grunts ]
Somebody help him , please ! Somebody help him !
The balcony ! - [ Groans ]
- Barry-y-y ! - [ Barry moans ]
- Help him ! Barry ! Help him ! Barry , no ! - [ Groans ]
Help him ! Please don 't !
Excuse me . Someone listen to me !
He 's got him- - hey , hey , hey ! What 's the problem ?
Help him ! He 's gonna kill him ! Who ? Who 's killin ' who ?
- Up in the balcony . - [ Officer ] All right , everybody , stay calm .
Get off of me !
[ Emcee ] You people just move back in your seats . Everything 's under control here .
Go back in your seats now , please . Thank you . Everybody move back .
Ma 'am , stay behind me , okay ?
[ Pageant official ] All right , ladies , places please . Places .
There 's nobody up here . I gotta tell you , this is really not my idea of a funny joke .
He was here . Who was here ?
The fisherman . He killed Barry ! Barry who ? Who ?
Who we talkin ' about ? There 's nobody up here . Come on . Let 's go downstairs .
Come on . There 's nobody up here .
Watch your step .
[ Emcee ] Ladies and gentlemen , if you 'll take your seats .
It was a false alarm . We 're gonna resume in a few minutes .
Ma 'am , I 'm gonna take you home .
Your parents are really worried about you . [ Crowd clapping ]
You have to believe me .
Why don 't you let me take you home , okay ?
[ Sniffles ] Uh , excuse me .
We 'll be needing this .
Oh , come on . Hurry , hurry , hurry .
[ Officer ] So , then he killed him with a fishhook . [ Helen ] Yes .
Did this fisherman use the same hook that cut your hair off ? [ Chuckles ]
No , he used scissors , asshole .
Look , okay , I know I sound delusional , but it 's true .
You know , I 've heard this story before ,
except the way I heard it it wasn 't a fisherman , it was an escaped mental patient ...
And he had a hook for a hand .
Well , we 're gonna have to take the alley .
Look , you little shit-stick , mayberry-ass reject ,
there 's been a murder , and you 're gonna fry in hell if you ignore it .
All right , I 'll tell you what I 'll do , okay ?
I 'll contact Barry 's parents and we 'll put out a search for him , all right ?
He was probably just playin ' a prank on you .
Oh , Jesus .
Listen , I 'm just gonna be a minute , all right ? I 'm gonna see if this fella needs help .
[ Woman over police radio , indistinct ]
[ Softly ] It 's- - it 's him .
What 's the trouble ?
That 's him ! Behind you !
Behind you !
- [ Groans ] - No-o-o-o !
[ Gurgling ]
[ Panting ]
No ! No !
[ Screams , panting continues ]
[ Whimpers ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Tapping on keyboard ]
" Susie Willis killed . Trapped in car .
" Driver unharmed . Survived by her father , Benjamin ,
a local fisherman . "
[ Whimpers ]
Elsa . Elsa !
Elsa ! Elsa !
Elsa , open the door ! Elsa !
Elsa !
Elsa , open the door , please ! Elsa , Jesus Christ , hurry !
Please !
Please ! Elsa ! What are you doing ?
Elsa ! Please , Elsa ! Open the door !
Jesus Christ , hurry , please ! Elsa , open the door now !
Please , let me in ! Oh , God ! Hurry , please , Elsa !
- I 'm coming . - Elsa !
Elsa ! Please !
You could have walked around . The broad street entrance is open .
I 'm being attacked !
[ Panting ] You 're what ?
Lock the other door . I 'll call the police . What is going on ?
Just do what I say , goddamn it !
♪ [ Soft rock , faintly ]
[ Exhales ] Come on . Come on .
[ Screaming ]
Elsa ?
♪ [ Continues faintly ]
[ Shouting ] Elsa , where are you ?
♪ [ Stops ]
[ Electrical switch clicks ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Grunts ] No !
No !
[ Grunts ]
[ Screams ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Groans ]
[ Coughing ]
[ Panting ] [ Fireworks exploding ]
♪ [ Marching drums ]
[ Fireworks continue exploding ]
[ Gasps ]
[ Screams , grunts ]
No !
[ Grunts , screams ]
[ Screams stop ]
♪ [ Trumpet playing " charge " ]
Ray .
Ray ! Ray !
Ray !
Julie , what are you doing here ? We didn 't kill David Egan .
It was someone else on the road that night . What are you talking about ?
- But they found David 's body in the water.Susie 's father , - yeah , I know . ' S a fishermabena
- but I think Ben Willis killed David Egan . - Wait a second .
You think Willis killed David , then we killed him ?
What if he didn 't die , Ray ? What if he 's still alive ?
- This is crazy . - [ Panting ]
Come aboard . Come inside .
No , we 've gotta find Helen and Barry . We will . We will .
[ Gasps ]
You .
Oh , my God . It 's you . What are you talkin ' about ?
Billy Blue . You went to Missy 's .
You 're- - you 're the friend . You 're the fisherman .
Wha- - I-I-I can explain . Julie , wait !
Julie ! Oh , shit !
Julie ! Stop it !
- [ Groans ] - [ Screams ]
[ Panting ] Oh . Oh , please help me . Please .
- Easy , child . - Please , I need to call the police .
- [ Coughs ] - On the boat . Inside . Hurry !
- [ Jiggling doorknob ] - Are you in some kind of trouble , child ?
Yes . Yeah . I 'm in a lot of trouble .
[ Chimes ]
That 's a shame ...
Being it 's fourth of July and all .
Kids like you should be out having fun :
Drinking , partying ,
running people over ,
getting away with murder ; Things like that .
You .
Ben Willis . Good .
I see you 've been doing your homework too .
Shit .
[ Clattering ]
[ Gasps ]
[ Motor starts ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Grunts , screams ]
Welcome aboard , Ray .
[ Panting ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Groans ]
Julie !
Ray !
- [ Loud groan ] - [ Screaming ]
[ Gasps ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Heavy footsteps approaching ]
[ Pounding on door ] No-o-o-o !
[ Screams ]
[ Pounding continues ]
[ Willis ] Open the door , Julie .
You got no place to hide .
[ Pounding continues ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Hatch opening ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Whimpers ] No . No .
[ Screams ] Come on , Julie !
Ray !
- [ Screaming ] - [ Groans ]
E.
Please , it was an accident . I know all about accidents .
And let me give you some advice : When you leave a man for dead ,
make sure he 's really dead !
[ Screaming ]
[ Woman over police radio , indistinct ]
[ Man muttering ]
We never killed anyone . This whole year was for- - I know .
The guilt was killin ' me .
And I had to know who he was .
That 's why I went to see Missy .
I 'm sorry I didn 't tell you , but ... I wanted you back .
I couldn 't lose you again .
I love you , Julie .
No one gets me the way you do .
I understand your pain .
Do you have any idea why this man would want you dead ?
None . No .
[ Officer ] Here it comes !
[ Sheriff ] Well , don 't worry .
The body 'll turn up . They usually do .
♪ [ Rock ]
Yeah , well , I made the Dean 's list .
Thank you very much . [ Giggles ]
No , I know . I miss you too . But I 'm gonna see you in a couple of weeks .
God , I cannot wait . I love New York .
No , of course I love you more .
Yes , I do . I love you and you know that . But you know what ?
I 've gotta take a shower . I 'm running really late .
[ Girl ] Hey , Julie , you got some mail .
Oh , thanks , Deb .
A towel .
Ray , don 't you start with me . Look , you , mister , can ravage me in two weeks .
Yes , I love you too . 'Kay , yes , I love you .
[ Laughs ]
[ Screams ]
♪
♪ [ scatting lyrics ]
♪ [ Scatting lyrics ]
♪ Well , I got a certain little girl she 's on my mind ♪
♪ no doubt about it she looks so fine ♪
♪ she 's the best girl that I ever had ♪
♪ except that 's the girl that made me feel so sad ♪
Ade me feel so sad ♪
♪ [ scatting lyrics ]
♪ Whoa ♪ [ Scatting lyrics ]
♪ Hey , now hush , hush thought I heard her calling my name now ♪
♪ now hush , hush she broke my heart but I love her just the same now ♪
♪ now hush , hush I thought I heard her call my name now ♪
♪ now hush , hush you broke my heart but I 'm not to blame now ♪
♪ early in the morning
♪ or late in the evening
♪ ah , gotta believe me , honey
♪ hush , hush thought I heard her calling my name now ♪
♪ now hush , hush she broke my heart but I love her just the same now ♪
♪ now hush , hush I thought I heard you call my name now ♪
♪ hush , hush you broke my heart but I 'm not to blame now ♪
♪ early in the morning
♪ or late in the evening
[ screams ]
♪ Ow
♪ oh ♪ [ Scatting lyrics ]
♪ [ Scatting lyrics ]
♪ Well , I got a certain little girl she 's on my mind ♪
♪ no doubt about it she looks so fine ♪
♪ she 's the best girl that I ever had ♪
♪ except that 's the girl that made me feel so sad ♪
♪ [ scatting lyrics ]
♪ Oh ♪ [ Scatting lyrics ]
♪ Hey , now hush , hush I thought I heard her calling my name now ♪
♪ hush , hush you broke my heart but I love her just the same now ♪
♪ hush , hu call my name now ♪
♪ hush , hush you broke my heart but I 'm not to blame now ♪
♪ early in the morning
♪ or late in the evening
[ screams ]
♪ Ow
♪ oh ♪ [ Scatting lyrics ]
♪ Oh , yeah ♪ [ Scatting lyrics ]
♪ Na , na-na-na
♪ na-na-na
♪ na-na ♪ whoa-oh